SHONGDOR N MAWROH (1) Featured

Immediately Available I Software Engineer with 1 year of experience seeking assignment in Backend Software Development with the following technologies Spring, Spring mvc, Spring boot, hibernate, JPA, rest api, java and other relevant technologies.



Current Location: Shillong Total Experience: 1 Year(s) 3 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Pune,Bengaluru / Bangalore,Hyderabad Notice Period: 15 Days or less
Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software development, Java, Spring, Spring mvc, Spring boot, hibernate, JPA, rest api, MySQL, DBMS, JSON, XML, Angular, typescript, HTML, CSS, Javascript, C, C++, Eclipse, postman, github, jira, Android

developer, Android Studio, gradle, JUnit, Maven

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Software engineer with 1 year experience in Tavant technologies at Bangalore | Master of Computer Applications(MCA) graduate | Specialised in front end as well as back end web development | Targeting assignments in backend software development | I am eager to learn new things and my work satisfaction is in the growth and development of the company. Skills: Software Engineer, Software development, Java, Spring, Spring mvc, Spring boot, hibernate, JPA, rest api, MySQL, DBMS, JSON, XML, Angular, typescript, HTML, CSS, Javascript, C, C++, Eclipse, postman, github, jira, Android developer, Android Studio

Work Experience

SELF WORK as Android Application Developer Mar 2020 to Jul 2020

Android Application developer.

Title: Khana lyngkot Android App (1000+ downloads)

(https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.khanalyngkot.basngewtynnad) Description: This is a stories inspirational app written in the local language Khasi

Publish Date in Play Store: 28 April 2020

Title: Khana lyngkot 2 Android App (1000+ downloads)

(https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.khanalyngkot.nabyntajongphi)

Description: Modified Version of Khana Lyngkot App, Added navigation drawer, Better UI Design

Publish Date in Play Store: 30 June 2020

Tavant Technologies India Pvt. Ltd. as Software Engineer

Dec 2018 to Mar 2020

Resolved issues within applications with a focus on optimizing application performance & scalability.

Adhered to company standards for coding.

Developed web applications, coded different modules; interacted with the BAs for requirement gathering; administering & adhering to SLA.

Environment: Worked on the front-end using Visual Studio ide (Angular 8), Languages Used: Typescript, HTML, CSS &

Other: postman

Description: Front end, rest API, controller, service, managing data received from the back-end, displaying data in table,

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=5337f10c09d0b0105029a7fad46af568580c5c531c1a58180b19435a5c5... pagination, sorting, hamburger add more columns display, fixed bugs, priming table, Validation of entered investor data form.

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from ST.EDMUNDS COLLEGE, SHILLONG in 2015

PG: MCA (Computers) from National Institute of Technology (NIT), Karnataka in 2018

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
JAVA			
Spring			
SPRING MVC			
spring boot			
Hibernate			
JPA			
REST API			
MySQL			
dbms			
JSON			
XML			
Angular 8			
TypeScript			
HTML			
CSS			
JavaScript			
С			
C++			
Eclipse			
postman			
GitHub			
JIRA			
Android Development			
Android Studio			
gradle			
MAVEN			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=5337f10c09d0b0105029a7fad46af568580c5c531c1a58180b19435a5c5...

English	Proficient
Hindi	
Khasi	Proficient

Projects

Project Title: Android Application Developer

Client: Self Work

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Mar 2020 - Jul 2020 Project Location: Shillong Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 2 Skill Used: Android Development, Android Studio, Android SDK, Java, XML,

Role Description: Android Developer Project Details: APPS DEVELOPED

Title: Khana lyngkot Android App (1000+ downloads)

(https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.khanalyngkot.basngewtynnad) Description: This is a stories inspirational app written in the local language Khasi

Publish Date in Play Store: 28 April 2020 Languages Used: Java, Group: 2 Developer: Shongdor N Mawroh

Content Writer: Shemphang Kurkalang, Others: Android studio, Gradle, XML layout UI

Title: Khana lyngkot 2 Android App (1000+ downloads)

(https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.khanalyngkot.nabyntajongphi)

Description: Modified Version of Khana Lyngkot App, Added navigation drawer, Better UI Design

Publish Date in Play Store: 30 June 2020 Languages Used: Java, Group: 2 Developer: Shongdor N Mawroh

Content Writer: Shemphang Kurkalang, Others: Android studio, Gradle, XML layout UI

Project Title: Flagstar Website Client: Flagstar Bank (USA Bank) Nature of Employment: Full Time

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: May 2019 - Aug 2019
Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 12

Skill Used: Angular, Typescript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap,others

Role Description: Software Engineer Project Details: Role: Software Engineer

Environment: Worked on the front-end using Visual Studio ide (Angular 8), Languages Used: Typescript, HTML, CSS &

Other: postman

Description: Front end, rest API, controller, service, managing data received from the back-end, displaying data in table, pagination, sorting, hamburger add more columns display, fixed bugs, priming table, Validation of entered investor data form.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time